the Rolling Stones start me up it's one
of my favorite people in
studio this is good morning Mumbai with
Rishi K sanjie mantri executive director
at IC Lombard how are you all good Richi
it's always a pleasure to be with you
thank you so much for getting me here
yeah I remember since the last time you
came in here you've been motivating me
to lose some weight and I have to hand
it to you for 3 months I really behave
myself I lost 10.5 kgs but you'd be very
unhappy to know that I'm slowly gaining
them back
yes yes I can say there's some more
scope on this side some more scope let's
today start about talking about Indian
tourism Trends there's some very
interesting trends that you have noticed
sanjie yeah clearly you can all notice
actually the number of time people are
going overseas these days uh as per the
data that is being made available to us
RI there are almost 25 million people
who have traveled out of India for an
overseas Holiday by 2020 is expected to
go to almost 50 million so there's a
huge surge in people going to different
parts of the world enjoying themselves
another critical Trend that is quite
evident is the Exotic holidays people
are seeking the number of searches that
happened to go to Gold Coast in
Australia or to go to Hanoi in Vietnam
or Prague so people are becoming more
and more exotic in terms of covering
multiple locations another piece which
is very very interesting is that the
millennial who are traveling typically
end up not going to one country when
they travel probably when we used to
travel to she we'll say okay we'll go to
One location be London hang in there for
a while and come back but now they want
to cover multiple countries so there's
enough enough and more that's happening
in terms of the Indian tourism and yes
Indians are traveling a lot more than
they used to in the past yeah actually
sanji's team has sent some very
interesting numbers I'm going to add on
to what he has just said this is uh the
travel aggregator Skys scanner in their
publication Skys scanner travel trends
for 2018 um this has noticed an average
increase of 80% in search from Indian
Travelers so we're talking Gold Coast on
Australia which sanjie just talked about
102 42% 142% Hanoi Vietnam 81% prag
Czech Republic 71% so fascinating stuff
there and in the midst of all this
there's obviously a need for travel
insurance clearly felt by Indian
Travelers sanjie clearly uh I think
there's one critical requirement that
exist when you travel overseas is that
you need to have travel insurance you'll
be surprised is she when I keep hearing
even with my own friends who are very
much educated living a very professional
life traveling very extensively saying
that they've gone to this and this place
my next question is did you take travel
insurance and they end up saying no we
didn't and then say what was the need
nothing will happen to me and
interestingly a study that we have done
among the number of claims that we have
seen so far clearly all problems are
agnostic to which age you belong to you
can have health issues you can have
accidents you can have uh probably an
emergency you can have trips getting
cancelled lot of things can happen like
giving you an example just to make my
point what happened in Bali because of
volcano eruption led to cancellations
flight delays people could not move out
for 1 week to 10 days from that
particular place now in that sort of an
excy it doesn't matter which age group
you belong to irres of what or where you
are travel insurance is a must to me
what's more interesting is the price of
a travel insurance is not Beyond $2 to
$50 so what are we talking of Vis is the
losses that can come on account of
health issues on account of loss of
baggage and on account of flight
cancellation or an accident that anyone
can face any point of time so clearly
there's no other way to travel overseas
travel insurance a key requirement
sanjie manri from IC Lombard right after
this song it's shiken Stevens you drive
me crazy Shen
Stevens glad that he's driving you crazy
on our playlist sanjie manri from IC
Lombard is here they've been Avage
supporters and get some sun through the
season and this is season five a really
important episode a conversation with
him about the need for travel
insurance this is good morning Mumbai
with Rishi K okay now there's a very
interesting survey that IC Lombard
conducted across 10 cities and I want
you to tell me about what are the major
concerns that Indian Travelers have or
what do they cite certainly Ri so some
of the major things that came out in the
survey was almost 50% of them felt that
personal accident can be a cause of
challenge when they in International
location 45 7% of almost people said
that they have a problem with with
respect to baggage loss 31% almost
feared hospitalization 46% of the
respondents said that loss of baggage
can be a prime concern so there enough
and More apprehensions in their mind
when they're traveling overseas in terms
of what can get inflicted on on them and
also some of the locations which are
slightly more worrisome slightly more
risky they believe that if they have a
travel insurance for that those places
they'll be more comfortable in terms of
going and visiting those places which
otherwise they won't so that's a
fascinating survey so he was actually
saying that if it's a troubl Tor area
even if there's conflict in their area
they feel security when they get that
travel insurance yes absolutely yeah
lovely so you know like you said
previously medical emergencies baggage
and passport Li uh loss are are things
that uh you know you're buying travel
insurance for would cancel flight
charges also be uh one of the reasons
they also covered yes cancel FL another
critical requirement whereby suppose you
get stuck in B and there's a cost that
is coming on account of rebooking
definitely Insurance can come in handy
and you can be reimbursed some critical
amount which will take care of the
losses yeah and you know the fact of the
matter is we had about 65 flights even
grounded domestically because of engine
trouble if you noticed last month so
that's a very very important aspect that
one needs to to cover so uh the claims
data uh can you run me through that is
especially with regards health related
risks yes clearly so we have access to
lot of claims data and almost 12 to 15%
is on account of accidents that the
customer face then we have health
related problem for almost 10 to 15%
again loss of baggage is a very common
thing we have been I mean we all have
gone through this mess isn't it R where
your baggage has got delayed sometimes
they Mis getting your baggage allog
together the baggages get lost the
losses that happen so you go through a
lot of challenge for the personal loss
of belonging and then comes the
Financial loss along with it all of that
can be taken care of more importantly
something which I mentioned we have
realized there's no connection of age
Vis what things can go wrong because
these are the losses which can come to
you agnostic to which age group you
belong to in fact we've seen lots of
youngsters who travel overseas isy end
up having health problem gastro issues
can come up you can have food can react
badly you may require hospitalization
the average cost on account of
hospitalization can go up to 1 to 1 and
a half lakhs when you get into trouble
in places like Europe or us and also
person accident the average loss in
terms of getting a customer back can go
to 25 to 30 lakh if I narrate to an
incident which will explain how
freakishly things can go wrong there
were some couple who were traveling to
Egypt and while having a camel ride
there was a fall from the camel which
took place consequent to that the person
vertebra got impacted Elan got impacted
there was no way the treatment could
have been done there because the medical
facilities a there available they were
not appropriate enough so we had to
evacuate the person get that person back
to Bombay the cost of that is almost
$50,000 fortunately the person had
travel insurance so that could come out
handy so in our mind things can go wrong
the cost is $2 $50 but the outflow in
case you have not taken an adequate
cover can go to am like $50,000 to maybe
a lack of a dollar so how do you manage
that it's just disproportionately very
high messages and back with sanjie manri
from IC Lombard a Maroon Five hit called
sugar sanjie manri executive director at
IC Lombard never dull moment when he's
in studio more
conversation this is good morning Mumbai
with Rishi K so sanjie you were telling
me that a typical medical claim in the
US can cost you anywhere between 1.75
lakhs to 2.5 lakhs and uh you know that
there is a little bit of a difference in
the shenen region and you gave me an
interesting example unfortunate example
of somebody whose uh whose spine was
impacted and they had to have an air
ambulance arranged luckily they had
travel insurance any other examples of
people caught with some kind of of
diseases or illness while their foreign
travel happened yes see I can share
another incidence in Australia which is
supposed to be one of the best places
when it comes to the ecosystem the
hygiene that they follow but one of the
customer who had traveled to Australia
suddenly started experiencing high fever
head vomiting daua initial clinical
examinations kind of told us that
there's some bit of infection in blood
and urine leading to eventually ospis
now this is something which is very
chaotic this requires multiple tests you
got to get admitted in the hospital go
through the whole process besides being
in the place which you are not certain
because the variables are just existing
in multiple manner the cost of getting
this whole of treatment covered was re
almost
$7,500 now that's really one that's a
lot of money to go when you on a holiday
for something which is critical but is
not part of your plans so all those sort
of cash flows can be arranged through an
insurance a cashless settlement can be
done and what we have done is we have
tied up with global experts in terms of
organizations who can manage this sort
of a thing you can reach out to us by
calling us we have got specific numbers
for USA and Europe requirement or you
can give a Miss call to us we can call
you back wherever whichever part of the
world you are in and ensure that those
experts come in and give you all the
assistance that is required and guide
you through the process to save the day
or maybe even you know your own health
let's come back to some Basics sanjie uh
allow me to ask you to be the dictionary
for us but what really is travel
insurance certainly Rishi travel
insurance takes care of medical l as
well as non-medical perils which an
insurer can have whether on a business
trip or on a pleasure trip medical
covers include hospitalizations due to
sudden inless and injuries as well as
treatment taken on outpatient basis
medical evacuation personal accident and
repatriations of remains are also
covered by the way trip related perils
like trip cancellation and Interruption
and trip delays due to various
contingencies baggage related covers
like total loss of checked in baggage
delay of checked in baggage loss of
baggage on person personal effects are
also covered in probably you know
another feature which I can add is you
know we provide for financial
emergencies in these cases now hijack
loss of passport can be covered personal
liability fire and blary at the place of
residence while one is traveling can
also be taken cover so there are
multiple covers that are available on
the travel insurance which can help the
traveler in a significant way after this
song we're going to come back and sanjie
is going to tell us the types of travel
insurance policies one can purchase here
are the chain smokers and everybody
hates me the chain smokers every
everybody hates me sanjie manri
executive director at IC lombar on the
types of travel insurance policies
now this is good morning Mumbai with
Rishi K so yeah you explained you're
very kind to explain what travel
insurance really is the types of
policies that one can purchase sanjie so
there is an option available uh Rishi
where you can buy for single trip if
you're not a frequent traveler but if
you're traveling very frequently maybe
three four times in a year what I
suggest is you buy a cover which is a
able for one year that kind of kind of
saves you from the administrative
trouble of picking up a policy every
time you are traveling now in terms of
the multiple trip that you buy for one
year what you can do is you can pick up
duration you can buy for 30 days 45 days
or 60 days so every time you're
traveling for that particular period you
will get the coverage in my sense most
of us who travel very frequently pick up
the one year one it really is hasslefree
it saves you for the complete
administrative Hassle and the coverage
in terms of the coverage that these
policies offer uh would you break it
down down into how much is for loss of
baggage baggage loss cover cancellation
Interruption missed flight cancellation
and of course personal liability yeah so
in terms of buying the policy first
thing first I think from 3 months to any
age limit travel insurance available
that's first point secondly almost up to
half a million Us doll is what the
coverage can come which is an account of
medical requirement or even the medical
evacuation cost that comes with it for
loss of baggage you can get cover up to
$22,000 you can have $500 coverage for
trip cancellation on account of the
change of ticketing that happens and you
can take a personal liability cover also
which can go up to a lck of a dollar so
there are multiple options that are
available and there are multiple plans
which are made available some of them
are basic plans some of them are
Platinum plans which are far more larger
amounts so whatever suits to you as a
for you as a traveler I suggest you
should pick it up but that being said do
make sure that you buy your travel
insurance when you're traveling sanjie
there are also some uh off the beaten
path covers you know it's like The Road
Less Traveled tell us about those
categories so now from icsa Lombard
perspective we do give insurance policy
for conscious service wherein we offer
assistance service such as doctor
appointments assistance with regard to
your Electrical Plumbing requirements at
home when your dep for your dependents
who are back in who are in India who do
not have access to you while you're
traveling overseas we can also cover the
political risk or the catastrophic
evacuation up to us 7,500 which also can
happen in certain uh cases I spoke about
it in terms of the catastrophic event
that happened in Bali which created with
the example which I spoke some time back
we can also give coverage to burglary
happening in your house up to to the
extent of 10 lakhs when you are out of
country or even give you home content
the losses which can happen at that
point of time when you are out of
country so there are those multiple
options that are there when you're
visiting overseas and in the case of an
excy where something happens to get the
person back the the The Mortals back in
the country there's an expense involved
that also can be specifically covered so
there are those specific unique features
which are there which can help you in
case things go wrong up ahead how can
one purchase travel insurance and
sanji's exciting life whereby he meets
some of the greatest sports people in
the world we're both sports fans we're
going to chat with about that before we
say bye-bye pictures as well as uh some
videos of sanjie manri hanging in studio
coming up on Twitter as well as Facebook
it's HRI sh i k y on Twitter and
Instagram and Facebook and facebook.com/
r1. mumum there's also platforms where
you can leave any comments I'm happy to
read them out on air or one space your
comment a name to find 5 3650 see you in
a bit some Reggae in the form of inner
circle and bad boys hardly bad boys
sanjie manri and yours truly in studio
he's executive director at ICI Lombard a
last leg of
conversation this is good morning Mumbai
with Rishi K so I have to round up with
where and how can one purchase travel
insurance from sanjie oh that's very
simple Rish uh all you got to do is log
on to our site
www.car.com and you cana finish the
process in just about 10 to 15 minutes
that's all it takes so it's quick easy
and smart you can actually do this when
you're sitting at the airport waiting
for boarding the flight so the whole
process is very easy all you got to do
is give your passport number put in your
basic details which are available with
you and the online document that you get
is valid enough to make claims in the
event of an excy so from our perspective
you have made it as easy as possible and
the event of you making a claim all you
got to do is give your policy number as
well as your passport number and we will
ensure sure that your claim is taken
care of so it's hasslefree it's online
besides this of course when you're
picking buying with your travel agent or
you're contacting anybody else you can
always request them we've got tie ups
with all of them where you will be
getting icsom insurance policy and it's
very important to know that one needs to
purchase the policy while while one is
in India that is before departing for
the foreign land that is critical you
cannot buy policy once you're overseas
your coverage has to start before you
board a flight from India that is a
critical requirement yes well before you
go I mean I have to say if you weren't a
friend of mine I'd be Mighty jealous of
you Goran ivich my God I remember him
winning Wimbledon and some of those
serves one couldn't even sight and uh
you you played some tennis with him
where was this and how did this happen
well yes we were on a trip to Melbourne
and got a chance to play with him what a
man he is I think uh for us and she you
share that thing any Sportsman who has
converted an activity into an art and it
has probably they excelled in it we
start worshiping it for me uh meeting a
legend himself was phenomenal someone
who picked up wom it was great to
understand his own journey in terms of
how he ended up winning because he had a
wild card entry that year and from there
on to go and win I think it's first of
its kind where someone with a wild card
entry end up winning the B London so in
terms of being jealous I think rishik
I'm more jealous of you you are among
celebrities all the time and there few
occasions you meet ordinary people like
me isn't it you're a kind man also I
have to say it's appalling the kind of
controversy that's happening and the
ball tampering that the the you know
bankra and Steve Smith as well as David
Warner have indulged in something that
Steve War would have been ashamed of and
you know that because you spent some
some time with Steve yes I did meet him
they play it very hard but they play
quite fairly and I think that's the way
you want to play every single sport
isn't it there's no intent to cheat you
just want to try your best and
eventually I think Sports is amazing you
may lose but you'll never be a loser
because you'll get up next day again and
probably start working hard and see if
you can beat it I like like what you
know I read Maria shara's Unstoppable
her autobiography and it was phenomenal
to see how she said that you got to be
sharp enough but you got to be dumb
enough to make sure that you are ready
when you're playing your next ball when
you're playing your next match so there
is clearly uh a sense of shock when I
heard what has gone through and the fact
that they've admitted there is reality
it's not even speculative whether they
did that or not to me it's unfortunate
but such things will happen there's too
much going around in terms of what
happens in commercial Sports they play
professionally they're so much involved
but winning at all counts is not poly
fair you got to balance it out and
hopefully this will also pass and
Cricket will stay what it is supposed to
be well a man who learns his vital
lessons from sport is always open my
doors are always open for him sanjie
manri absolute pleasure take care of
yourself thank you thank you so much
Rishi it was a pleasure being on 94.3
Radio 1 thank you so much Soul Asylum
Runaway Train